PRAVEEN KUMAR

HTML Developer

% 7827598996☑ link2pk@gmail.com♥ Gurgaon, India

RECENT PROJECTS

Flydocs https://beta.flydocsuat.com/

Flydocs is an asset management solution provider with the aviation industry's most comprehensive solution for creating value out of aircraft maintenance data. It offer the tools and expertise that allow all industries to drive sustainable innovation to help build the future of the commercial aviation asset lifecycle.

ANIA MANAGEMENT https://www.aniamanagement.com/

ANIA Management is a privately-owned company that specializes in property management, owner/investor, construction and maintenance services.

Cosmic Byte https://www.thecosmicbyte.com/

Cosmic Byte is the Best in Class gaming gear that exudes style, Power and Performance. It Brings affordable gaming to India.

Savvy https://savvyapp.com.au/

It was a web and mobile based fintech solution for advisors and users so that users can properly manage their finances. Based on users' expenses on a weekly/monthly basis, advisors give advice to their clients according to their expenditure.

Open Charity https://link2pk.github.io/open-charity

A platform collaborating charities and partners and sharing open solutions and ideas to create value in the digital space.

Treasure https://tresure.com.au

Treasure Mobile app is used to manage income and gain financial freedom.

Ebill https://link2pk.github.io/ebill

Australian bills payment mobile app. This application was made for utilities bill payment through a mobile application.

ABCBank https://link2pk.github.io/ABCBank

International https://link2pk.github.io/international

Fitness Time https://link2pk.github.io/fitness-time

Six8 https://app.six8.com.au

ConsultThompson http://www.consultthompson.com

RMR Marmo https://www.rmrmarmo.com

360 Degree World https://www.360degreeworld.com

Final Call https://www.finalcall.com.au

Streamhear http://www.streamhear.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Developer, ValueCoders Services LLP (A Vinove Company)	Oct 2022 - Present
 Working for their client named FE fundinfo 	Aug 2022 - Present
Software Developer, ValueCoders Services LLP (A Vinove Company)	Dec 2021 - Oct 2022
 Worked for their client named Flydocs India Pvt. Ltd. 	Feb 2022 - Aug 2022
Senior Software Engineer, Appster LLP	Oct 2017 - Dec 2018
Software Engineer, Appster LLP	Apr 2016 - Oct 2017
Web Developer, Appster LLP	Dec 2014 - Mar 2016
Designer, Convergent Technologies	Mar 2014 - Dec 2014
Web Designer, Sagacious Softwares (now Digital HIVE)	Aug 2013 - Mar 2014
UI Designer, Webreinvent Technologies Pvt Ltd	Aug 2012 - Jul 2013

SKILLS

- Design to HTML conversion.
- Mobile-first responsive UI development.
- Cross-browser/device compatibility check.
- jQuery plugins customization and implementation.
- To provide effective solution for design(UI/UX) feasibility on frontend.
- Support for change requests and support to backend developers.
- Git for keeping source code.
- Agile methodology and daily scrum.

TOOLS i use for my day-to-day work

HTML5, CSS3, CSS Grid, CSS Flexbox, SCSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, JS, WordPress, Git, Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop, Visual Studio Code, Jira, Azure DevOps, Zoho projects, Microsoft Azure Storage Explorer, Microsoft Teams etc.

EDUCATION

MSc in Information Technology, De Montfort University, Leicester

2011

BE in Electronics and Communications, Institute of Technology & Management, Gurgaon

(now NorthCap University)